Guide to the Washington State University Building Arts Committee Records 1974-1979
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington State University Building Arts Committee Records
1974-1979
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 372
.5 linear feet of shlef space 1 box
Records relating to the beginning and first few years of Washington State University’s Building Arts Committee, and to projects it oversaw. The committee arose out of the state of Washington’s Art in Public Places (AIPP) program, which designated ½ of 1% of building construction funds to go to art.
In 1974, the state of Washington’s legislature authorized an Art in Public Places (AIPP) program, which required that ½ of 1% of building construction funds had to go to art. To deal with selecting and approving this art on campus, in 1975 Washington State University created a Building Arts Committee, which was comprised of faculty, staff, and students.
The general committee records consists of correspondence to/from the committee chair or relating to the committee’s work, meeting minutes, and documentation created by the committee or others which informed the process of selecting artworks. Project records may include correspondence relating to the project, specs for the artists’ use, floorplans and grounds plans of the area, notes on the selection process, and information from the selected artist.
The collection is in two main series, the first being general committee records, and the second relating to specific projects. Within each series are subject or project-based files, arranged alphabetically. Several of the projects comprise subseries of their own, again containing subject-based files, organized alphabetically. At the end of the projects series is one large folder which contains items applying to multiple projects. Items are organized chronologically within each file.
Project files are organized by the names used in the papers here, many of which have subsequently changed. In the file list below, current (as of 2017) building names are included parenthetically, as is the name of the selected work and the artist where those are known
This collection is open and available for research use.
These materials were donated to the Washington State University Libraries’ Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC) on September 9th, 1981, by Pauline Lilje, former chair of the Building Arts Committee. They were retained as UA1981-23.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Building Arts Committee.
Public art.
Colleges and Universities.; Washington (State)
- General Business
  - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting minutes, 1975-1976 (Folder 2)
  - Regulations and restrictions: NEA, RCW, WSAC. 1974-1978 (Folder 3)
  - Selection guidelines, 1976 (Folder 4)
- Projects
  - Agricultural Science (Hulbert and Clark Halls. Untitled, by Larry Tate)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Location and artwork. Undated (Folder 6)
  - Biosciences (Eastlick Hall. Untitled, by Clint Brown)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Floorplans and grounds, ca. 1974 (Folder 8)
    - Proposal (accepted) documentation, 1976 (Folder 9)
  - Computer Science - Mathematics (IT Building. Stempost, by James Hansen), 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Intercollegiate Center for Nursing Education, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Johnson Hall mural, 1979 (Folder 12)
  - Veterinary Animal Holding Facilities, 1977-1978 (Folder 13)
  - Veterinary Science (Bustad Hall. X-Position by Robert Ellison)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Floorplans, grounds, and specifications, 1975-1977 (Folder 15)
    - Proposal reviews, 1977 (Folder 16)
    - Selection and approval, 1977 (Folder 17)
  - Veterinary Science (Bustad) mural, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Multi-facilities: Agricultural Science, Biosciences, and Veterinary Science, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)